Maxime Dupuis

Full-stack Web Developer

Contact me

Montréal, Canada

☐ mdupuis@hotmail.ca

L 514-546-0054

Az French, English

Find me online

maxdup.dev

github.com/maxdup

in linkedin.com/in/maxdup



At a glance

10

Years of experience working as a developer

Occupying roles such as

- Full-stack developer
- Frontend developer
- Mobile developer
- Game developer

With companies such as

- 3dverse
- Soulzone inc.
- Valve Corporation

Hi, I'm Maxime, a Montréal-based web developer.

I tend to be product-oriented. To me, the end-user experience is the only measure of success.

That being said... there's always more to it than meets the eye. That's why I like to go deep into every facets of what makes software tick, whether it be in the frontend or backend.

Technical Skills

Programming Languages

TypeScript, JavaScript, HTML5, CSS3, SCSS, WebGL, Java, Python, C#, PHP

UI Frameworks and Technologies

React, Angular, VueJs, AngularJs, Ionic, Wordpress, WPF

Backend Frameworks and Technologies

NodeJS, Spring Boot, Flask, Django, .net, Elixir, SQL, MongoDB, RabbitMQ.

Infrastructure and tools

Webpack, Git, Jira, Sphinx, NodeJs, Docker, Nginx

Professional Experiences

3dverse

Fullstack developer (2024)

I contributed to the enhancement of the platform's developer console, pushing forward cutting edge 3D technologies for the web. I led the development of a powerful graph editor to drive 3d engine capabilities. Led the development of a government-funded innovation project, overseeing its successful execution of the key features.

Soulzone

Frontend developer (2016-2023)

I led the comprehensive frontend development of an innovative multimedia platform, prioritizing the creation of immersive and captivating user experiences. I've contributed to the platform's distinctiveness and heightened visual presentation by meticulously implementing fully custom UI components as well as a completely custom CSS style, ensuring a unified and refined appearance across all aspects of the platform.

Valve Corporation

Game Developer (2015 and 2022)

As a freelance Level Designer, I had the honor of being contracted by Valve on two occasions to contribute to their content updates for the game Team Fortress 2. I conceptualized, designed, and delivered original and groundbreaking game levels. My responsibilities encompassed conceptualisation, 3D art, environmental design, game balance, scripting and optimization for each project.

Agora

Tech co-founder/full-stack/mobile developer (2016-2017)

Being a Tech co-founder, I've had to architect a scalable backend system that effectively manages data flow, user authentication, and API integrations to support seamless functionality across all platforms. Additionally, I've had to engineer hybrid mobile applications that synchronized with the backend, ensuring consistent user experiences and optimal performance.

Tenscores

Full-stack developer (2014-2014)

During my brief tenure at Tenscores, I played a key role in enhancing the user experience for account management. Additionally, I undertook significant backend improvements that resulted in a remarkable 500-fold reduction in API usage. This, in turn, substantially lowered operational expenses associated with critical platform features.

Key technologies

- NodeJS
- React
- Redux
- OpenAPI
- ThreeJS

Key technologies

- Vue
- Webpack
- Elixir
- PostgreSQL
- FFmpeg

Key technologies

- Source Engine
- Hammer Editor
- VScript
- 3ds Max

Key technologies

- iOS / Android
- Angular
- Ionic / Cordova
- Python
- Flask
- MongoDB

Key technologies

- AngularJS
- CoffeeScript
- Python
- Pyramid
- Adwords API

Education

- Software Engineering École de technologie supérieure Postponed 2014 - 2015
- Management Computing Collège Montmorency
 Graduated 2014

Projects

As a passionate web developer and game developer, I have been actively involved in the open-source community, with a particular focus on the Python ecosystem.

I have created multiple libraries and tools which I actively develop and maintain.

My commitment to code quality is reflected in my projects through rigorous testing, continuous integration, and comprehensive documentation.

Come see my Github profile!

• github.com/maxdup

Web Development

Flask-favicon

A Python Flask extension that generates and serves favicon assets for diverse platforms.

Flask-cache-manifest

A Python Flask extension for serving hashed assets via cache-busting manifests.

Game Development

pySourceSDK

A collection of Python libraries designed to handle various game asset file types.

The Orange Toolbox

A set of debugging and automation tools tailored for the Source engine.

CompilePal

Build tools and bundler designed for Source engine level creation.